<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title><![CDATA[Kajal Sah - Kajal Sah]]></title><description><![CDATA[Thoughts, stories and ideas.]]></description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><image><url>http://localhost:2368/favicon.png</url><title>Kajal Sah - Kajal Sah</title><link>http://localhost:2368/</link></image><generator>Ghost 4.5</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 20:44:47 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/author/kajal/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[outreachy.init() -- My Intro]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p></p><blockquote> &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0;<strong> Awesome start to the summer :)</strong></blockquote><p>Hello World!! This is my first blog, let me briefly introduce myself. I&apos;m <strong>Kajal Sah</strong>, a computer application graduate. I live in Arunachal Pradesh, India -- a beautiful hill station located at the base of the Himalayas, the</p>]]></description><link>http://localhost:2368/outreachy/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60b2180049bc2b306c237e2b</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Kajal Sah]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 12:05:21 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2021/05/start-2.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2021/05/start-2.png" alt="outreachy.init() -- My Intro"><p></p><blockquote> &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0;<strong> Awesome start to the summer :)</strong></blockquote><p>Hello World!! This is my first blog, let me briefly introduce myself. I&apos;m <strong>Kajal Sah</strong>, a computer application graduate. I live in Arunachal Pradesh, India -- a beautiful hill station located at the base of the Himalayas, the highest mountain range in the world. </p><p> &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0;About <strong>hobbies</strong>!! Playing <strong>sports</strong> is my favorite pastime. During school days I went for many tournaments in Athletics and Kho-Kho. In college, I only played in one tournament, that too we lost (bad luck). So if i&apos;m not on my desktop, you can find me on the playground or else in the kitchen as I like <strong>cooking</strong> too (although I&apos;m not so good at it). I love trying out new recipes from various parts of the world.</p><h2 id="talking-about-core-values"><em>Talking About Core Values!!</em></h2><ul><li><strong>Discipline</strong> has become a part of my life as I don&apos;t believe wasting time on unnecessary things. I&apos;m more focused on my goals and always keeps my work up on time. I do study, play, eat, sleep &amp; wake up well on time, thus I stay active the entire day.</li></ul><blockquote><strong>Discipline creates habits, habits make routines, and routines makes what you are as a person.</strong></blockquote><ul><li>I strongly feel that I was able to delve into open source thanks to my <strong>perseverance.</strong> In any situation, the best attitude is to never give up. Challenges, failures are something that we will get throughout our life, so why not face them! and eventually, perseverance will lead you to your achievements. That&apos;s what I believe.</li><li><strong>Hope</strong> reduces feelings of helplessness, increases happiness, reduces stress, and improves our quality of life. <strong>That&apos;s why hope is so important for me</strong>. Hope for getting through tough times, but also for meeting everyday goals. </li></ul><blockquote> <strong>Everything that is done in the world is done by hope. &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0;- Martin Luther </strong></blockquote><h2 id="my-motivation-for-outreachy"><em>My Motivation For Outreachy?</em></h2><p>I was always keen to learn about <strong>open source contribution</strong>. Back in the year 2019, a friend of mine has suggested me outreachy. I researched a lot about it and was all set but due to some circumstances I could not apply at that time. I had been waiting for a long time to be a part of the outreachy organization. And yessss!!!!! <strong>The day is finally here :)</strong></p><p>Moving to, How I got selected as <a href="https://www.outreachy.org/">Outreachy</a> Intern for <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/">Mozilla Firefox</a>!!</p><h3 id="contribution-period">Contribution Period!!</h3><p>So, we had an <strong>Initial Application Round </strong>before Contribution Period. Where basic details were asked along with some essay type questions. After clearing the initial application round, I started exploring various open-source projects that were relevant to my interests. Due to my prior experience, I was looking for organizations that require knowledge of Javascript. I found Mozilla Firefox to be extremely aligned with my interests. I have been using Firefox for a very long time now and contributing to it was like a dream for me. I contacted my mentor Emma and asked for starter bugs. Thanks to her constant guidance, I was able to submit a few patches before the contribution deadline. Thankfully, the Outreachy organizers and Mozilla mentors found my contributions to be good enough to offer me an internship. I am very excited to embark on this beautiful journey for three months. &#xA0;</p><h2 id="the-way-ahead"><em>The Way Ahead!</em></h2><p>Right from week 1, I am into solving bugs. Currently, I am working on two bugs pertaining to <strong>the screenshot module of firefox </strong>(<a href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1679313">https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1679313</a> and <a href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1710635">https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1710635</a>). I also had my first meeting this week where I introduced myself to my mentors <strong>Sam Foster </strong>and<strong> Emma Malysz</strong> and discussed plans for this and subsequent weeks. I hope to keep working at this pace and seek help from mentors whenever I am stuck. Hope to have a great learning experience along with great opportunities that come along with Outreachy.</p><p></p><p></p><p> &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; </p><p></p><p> &#xA0;</p><p></p><p> &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0;</p><h3></h3><p></p><p></p><h3></h3><p> &#xA0; </p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>