<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title><![CDATA[Kajal Sah]]></title><description><![CDATA[Thoughts, stories and ideas.]]></description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><image><url>http://localhost:2368/favicon.png</url><title>Kajal Sah</title><link>http://localhost:2368/</link></image><generator>Ghost 4.5</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 10:42:48 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Peaks And Valleys]]></title><description><![CDATA[<blockquote><strong>The struggle is real!</strong> </blockquote><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2021/06/Angry-man-at-computer.png" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy" width="800" height="600" srcset="http://localhost:2368/content/images/size/w600/2021/06/Angry-man-at-computer.png 600w, http://localhost:2368/content/images/2021/06/Angry-man-at-computer.png 800w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p><strong>Struggle starts the moment we start <em>professional communication!! </em></strong>One of the most valuable skills I&apos;m learning in this internship is the ability to speak with people in a <strong>professional setting</strong>. Working in a professional setting for the first time can be difficult to get</p>]]></description><link>http://localhost:2368/untitled/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60c287783b7bd13a186648ad</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Kajal Sah]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 21:50:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><strong>The struggle is real!</strong> </blockquote><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2021/06/Angry-man-at-computer.png" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy" width="800" height="600" srcset="http://localhost:2368/content/images/size/w600/2021/06/Angry-man-at-computer.png 600w, http://localhost:2368/content/images/2021/06/Angry-man-at-computer.png 800w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p><strong>Struggle starts the moment we start <em>professional communication!! </em></strong>One of the most valuable skills I&apos;m learning in this internship is the ability to speak with people in a <strong>professional setting</strong>. Working in a professional setting for the first time can be difficult to get used to. But it is the best way to learn how to navigate the working world through real-life.</p><blockquote><strong>Learning Starts With Questioning!!</strong></blockquote><p>Initially, I was very <strong>hesitant</strong> to ask questions to my mentors, I thought they would judge me for asking such trivial questions. But I was totally wrong, they are very friendly and helpful. Whenever I get stuck in my work or I don&apos;t understand something, I immediately ask them and they are always there to help me out. This has happened to me many times when I came across some new words in the vocabulary but my mentors made sure I understood those terms and we also have a good discussion.</p><p>There are several <strong>vocabulary terms </strong>that I recently learned that I was unaware of before and during the internship application period. One of them was the term <strong>&apos;find bar&apos;</strong> which is a browser component of Firefox (<em>Use the Ctrl+F keyboard shortcut. Click on the menu button , and then click Find</em>). We need to type a search phrase into the find bar&apos;s field and Firefox will start highlighting instances of your search phrase as you type. </p><p>Another term was <strong>&apos;rebasing&apos;</strong>. Rebasing is often used in open-source version control to move the predecessor of a commit to another more recent commit. When I was solving a bug, it took me a week and there were some changes made to the same file. When I updated my patch on phabricator, the patch was not mergeable due to some conflict. Now, to solve that merge, my mentor <strong>Emma </strong>suggested rebasing my commit to the latest commit on the central branch. I was unsure about what that means. Thankfully, she has also suggested to me the steps to achieve that. To further understand that, I explored various tutorials and what that means that what are the advantages of a rebase. After reading some of the articles, I understood that rebasing is done to ensure a clean merge with the working branch. I am very much impressed by the capabilities of version control systems like <strong>git</strong> and<strong> mercurial</strong>. I will continue to keep learning such terminologies which would help me in cleaning landing my patches in the future.</p><p>Working as an intern and completing imperative tasks for my company gave me confidence to <strong>believe in myself</strong>. The completion of these tasks and appreciation from my mentors created a <strong>sense of accomplishment</strong> or something that I took pride in :)</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2021/06/iStock-1163542789-945x630.jpg" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy" width="945" height="630" srcset="http://localhost:2368/content/images/size/w600/2021/06/iStock-1163542789-945x630.jpg 600w, http://localhost:2368/content/images/2021/06/iStock-1163542789-945x630.jpg 945w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p> With that I conclude, Intern life can be tough as we only get a short period of time to make a lasting impression. However, its fun too.</p><h3 id="work-hard-enjoy-your-internship"><strong> </strong>Work Hard &amp; Enjoy Your Internship!! </h3>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[outreachy.init() -- My Intro]]></title><description><![CDATA[<figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2021/05/start-4.png" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy" width="1080" height="620" srcset="http://localhost:2368/content/images/size/w600/2021/05/start-4.png 600w, http://localhost:2368/content/images/size/w1000/2021/05/start-4.png 1000w, http://localhost:2368/content/images/2021/05/start-4.png 1080w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><blockquote> &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0;<strong> Awesome start to the summer :)</strong></blockquote><p>Hello World!! This is my first blog, let me briefly introduce myself. I&apos;m <strong>Kajal Sah</strong>, a computer application graduate. I live in Arunachal Pradesh, India -- a beautiful hill station located at the base of the Himalayas, the</p>]]></description><link>http://localhost:2368/outreachy/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60b2180049bc2b306c237e2b</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Kajal Sah]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 12:05:21 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2021/05/start-4.png" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy" width="1080" height="620" srcset="http://localhost:2368/content/images/size/w600/2021/05/start-4.png 600w, http://localhost:2368/content/images/size/w1000/2021/05/start-4.png 1000w, http://localhost:2368/content/images/2021/05/start-4.png 1080w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><blockquote> &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0;<strong> Awesome start to the summer :)</strong></blockquote><p>Hello World!! This is my first blog, let me briefly introduce myself. I&apos;m <strong>Kajal Sah</strong>, a computer application graduate. I live in Arunachal Pradesh, India -- a beautiful hill station located at the base of the Himalayas, the highest mountain range in the world. </p><p> &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0;About <strong>hobbies</strong>!! Playing <strong>sports</strong> is my favorite pastime. During school days I went for many tournaments in Athletics and Kho-Kho. In college, I only played in one tournament, that too we lost (bad luck). So if i&apos;m not on my desktop, you can find me on the playground or else in the kitchen as I like <strong>cooking</strong> too (although I&apos;m not so good at it). I love trying out new recipes from various parts of the world.</p><h2 id="talking-about-core-values"><em>Talking About Core Values!!</em></h2><ul><li><strong>Discipline</strong> has become a part of my life as I don&apos;t believe wasting time on unnecessary things. I&apos;m more focused on my goals and always keeps my work up on time. I do study, play, eat, sleep &amp; wake up well on time, thus I stay active the entire day.</li></ul><blockquote><strong>Discipline creates habits, habits make routines, and routines makes what you are as a person.</strong></blockquote><ul><li>I strongly feel that I was able to delve into open source thanks to my <strong>perseverance.</strong> In any situation, the best attitude is to never give up. Challenges, failures are something that we will get throughout our life, so why not face them! and eventually, perseverance will lead you to your achievements. That&apos;s what I believe.</li><li><strong>Hope</strong> reduces feelings of helplessness, increases happiness, reduces stress, and improves our quality of life. <strong>That&apos;s why hope is so important for me</strong>. Hope for getting through tough times, but also for meeting everyday goals. </li></ul><blockquote> <strong>Everything that is done in the world is done by hope. &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0;- Martin Luther </strong></blockquote><h2 id="my-motivation-for-outreachy"><em>My Motivation For Outreachy?</em></h2><p>I was always keen to learn about <strong>open source contribution</strong>. Back in the year 2019, a friend of mine has suggested me outreachy. I researched a lot about it and was all set but due to some circumstances I could not apply at that time. I had been waiting for a long time to be a part of the outreachy organization. And yessss!!!!! <strong>The day is finally here :)</strong></p><p>Moving to, how I got selected as <a href="https://www.outreachy.org/">Outreachy</a> Intern for <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/">Mozilla Firefox</a>!!</p><h3 id="contribution-period">Contribution Period!!</h3><p>So, we had an <strong>Initial Application Round </strong>before Contribution Period. Where basic details were asked along with some essay type questions. After clearing the initial application round, I started exploring various open-source projects that were relevant to my interests. Due to my prior experience, I was looking for organizations that require knowledge of Javascript. I found Mozilla Firefox to be extremely aligned with my interests. I have been using Firefox for a very long time now and contributing to it was like a dream for me. I contacted my mentor Emma and asked for starter bugs. Thanks to her constant guidance, I was able to submit a few patches before the contribution deadline. Thankfully, the Outreachy organizers and Mozilla mentors found my contributions to be good enough to offer me an internship. I am very excited to embark on this beautiful journey for three months. &#xA0;</p><h2 id="the-way-ahead"><em>The Way Ahead!</em></h2><p>Right from week 1, I am into solving bugs. Currently, I am working on two bugs pertaining to <strong>the screenshot module of firefox </strong>(<a href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1679313">https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1679313</a> and <a href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1710635">https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1710635</a>). I also had my first meeting this week where I introduced myself to my mentors <strong>Sam Foster </strong>and<strong> Emma Malysz</strong> and discussed plans for this and subsequent weeks. I hope to keep working at this pace and seek help from mentors whenever I am stuck. Hope to have a great learning experience along with great opportunities that come along with Outreachy.</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>